### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ mehdijalalpour (LinkedIn) sites.google.com/site/ mehdijalalpour/ (Other) works.bepress.com/ mehdi\_jalalpour/ (Other)

## Top Skills

Matlab Structural Analysis

Finite Element Analysis

### Certifications

Intro to Data Science with Python Convolutional Neural Networks Data Science Foundations: Python Scientific Stack

Building a Recommendation System with Python Machine Learning & Al

Art and Science of Machine Learning

#### **Publications**

Forecasting demand for health services: Development of a publicly available toolbox

Comparing methods of targeting obesity interventions in populations: An agent-based simulation

Google Flu Trends Spatial Variability Validated Against Emergency Department Influenza-Related Visits

# Mehdi Jalalpour

Data Scientist at KPMG

Orange County, California Area

## Summary

Mehdi is a published data scientist with six years of experience in turning data into insights using Python, and R. Mehdi has built machine learning platforms and models for healthcare institutions, local law enforcement and governments to improve operations and resource utilization.

His recent interest include using sequence RNNs for speech recognition. Mehdi is also experienced in the application of optimization and stochastic simulation to a variety of engineering and health care related projects.

## Experience

### **KPMG US**

Senior Associate, Data Scientist December 2017 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Orange County, California Area

Cleveland State University Assistant Professor August 2013 - December 2017 (4 years 5 months)

- Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area
- Principal investigator on several data analytics and optimization projects
- Taught courses on structural mechanics, reliability and stochastic processes
- Supervised graduate students research

Johns Hopkins University 5 years

Research assistant September 2008 - August 2013 (5 years)

- Structural design optimization under manufacturing uncertainties.
- · Multidisciplinary research with School of Medicine on health care delivery optimization.

 Multidisciplinary research with School of Public Health on childhood obesity.

Teaching assistant

September 2009 - May 2011 (1 year 9 months)

Courses:

-Statics and mechanics of Materials (60+ students) http://www.ce.jhu.edu/lori/statics/

- Probability and statistics (100+ students)
- Systems modeling and simulations

Kala Electeric

Structural Engineer II
May 2006 - July 2008 (2 years 3 months)

• On-site representative and problem solver

Performed field inspection of soil excavation and soil stabilization projects.

Verified that contractor work was in compliance with construction documents of industrial warehouses, office buildings, underground tunnels, and pipe racks.

Proposed and inspected the construction of diversionary dams to protect highvoltage electricity transmission lines from floods.

Structural Engineer

Designed steel and concrete structural systems for various production and administrative buildings.

## Education

The Johns Hopkins University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Civil Engineering Systems · (2011 - 2013)

The Johns Hopkins University

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Civil Engineering (2008 - 2011)

University of Tehran

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Structural Engineering · (2003 - 2005)